hypertext markup language or html is a language that defines the structure of
超文本标记语言或 html 是一种定义网页内容结构的语言
content on a webpage development started in 1989 at cern by tim berners-lee who
由蒂姆·伯纳斯·李 于 1989 年在欧洲核子研究中心研发的
had just invented the world's first web browser world wide web the origin of www
那时他刚刚发明了世界上第一个网络浏览器万维网
but he needed a publishing language to display content within it so he chose a
但他需要发布一种语言来显示其中的内容
syntax based on the standard generalized markup language which uses opening and
因此他选择了基于标准通用标记语言的语法
closing tags to provide meaning to otherwise unorganized text like h4
该语言使用开始和结束标记为其他无组织的文本提供含义
heading p for paragraph and most importantly a for anchor to link to a
例如h4用于标题，p 用于段落，最重要的是 a 用于链接到不同网页
different web page the language underwent many changes during the
HTML语言在互联网最初兴起期间经历了许多变化
initial rise of the internet and was standardized as html5 in 2008 the
在2008年被标准化为html5
version we know and love today modern html contains tags to handle a variety
我们今天了解和喜爱的版本 现代 html 包含处理各种
of different media types like video audio and canvas to draw custom graphics
不同媒体类型的标签如视频音频，画布可以动态绘制自定义图形
on the fly the typical html element starts with an opening and closing tag
典型的 html 元素以中间的开始和结束标记开始，
in the middle we have content which might be text or additional html
我们的内容可能是文本或称为子元素的附加html元素
elements called children the opening tag may also have one or more attributes
开始标签也可能有一个或多个属性
which are key value pairs that can customize the appearance or behavior of
这些属性的键值对可以自定义元素的外观或行为
the element to build your first web page create a file named index.html this file
来构建您的第一个名为 index.html的个网页文件
contains a hierarchy of nodes based on the document object model or dom a
此文件包含基于文档对象模型或 dom 的节点层次结构
webpage starts with an html tag and has exactly two children a head and a body
网页以 html 标记开头，并且正好有两个子元素一个head和一个body
the head contains things that aren't directly shown in the webpage like a
head包含网页中未直接显示的内容
title or a meta tag to give the page a description but notice how the meta
例如标题，meta标记用于为页面提供描述
element has no closing tag closing tags are generally optional when an element
但需请注意meta元素没有结束标签，当元素完全独立时结束标签通常是可选的
is fully self-contained the body contains the actual ui for the end user
正文包含最终用户的实际UI
we might start with an h1 heading followed by a paragraph of content to
我们可以从一个 h1 标题开始，然后给一段内容通过使用
add an image we use an image tag which you'll notice is self-closing then
一个image标签来添加一个图像而且它是自动关闭的
define the source attribute as the file path to the image and you'll want to
然后将源属性定义为图像的文件路径
give it an old description to make it accessible to robots and screen readers
你需要给它一个旧的描述方便机器人可以访问它
what makes web pages revolutionary though is their ability to link to other
浏览器使网页具有革命性的原因在于它们能够链接到信息高速公路上的其他网页
web pages on the information super highway use an anchor tag to create a
使用锚点标记创建链接
link then define the href attributes as the webpage that you want to navigate to
然后将 href 属性定义为需要导航到的网页
when clicked html also provides structural tags like division or div
它还提供了结构标签，如 Division 或 div
which are often used to group elements together where they can be styled to
这些标签通常用于将元素组合在一起
represent complex ui elements like navbars when you're happy with your code
当您高兴时还可以为他们设置复杂的 ui 元素，如导航栏
grab the full file path to the html file and paste it into any web browser
使用您的代码获取 html 文件的完整文件路径并将其粘贴到任何
congratulations you just built your first website this has been hypertext
Web浏览器中恭喜您刚刚建立了第一个网站
markup language in 100 seconds hit the subscribe button so you don't miss the
这就是HTML的100秒简介
upcoming sequels thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，下次见